Christopher Glinka

Edmonton, Alberta, CA 587 778 8210 glinkachris@gmail.com

SUMMARY

A motivated Software Developer with a lifelong passion for technology and a strong desire for continuous learning. I started my career in the retail and services industry and now after three years of technical education from NAIT's Digital Media and IT program, I am applying my skills where I can, to make a difference. My recent role at Code Ninjas sparked a newfound love for teaching coding to kids and this led me to start and head a weekly teen night providing a space for like-minded individuals to connect, explore interests, and learn together.

EXPERIENCE

Code Ninjas, St. Albert — Summer Camp Director & Supervisor

2021 - 2023

I created and cultivated an engaging and educational experience for young learners, aged 5 - 16. I led a team of instructors, oversaw center operations, and ensured kids had a safe, enjoyable, and enriching experience while exploring the world of coding and technology.

Starbucks, Namao — Barista

2021

I expertly prepared and served a variety of beverages and food items, ensuring that each one met the company's high-quality standards. I took pride in creating a welcoming atmosphere, providing outstanding customer service, and maintaining a clean and organized workspace.

GameStop Canada, St. Albert — Senior Sales Associate/Key Holder

2014 - 2020

I played a pivotal role in ensuring an exceptional shopping experience for all customers. My responsibilities included but weren't limited to assisting customers in finding the perfect gaming products, providing in-depth knowledge about the latest releases, and offering insights into gaming accessories and hardware.

PROFILES

Portfolio: cglinkadesigns.com

GitHub: CGlinka95

LinkedIn: Christopher Glinka

SKILLS

Team Oriented

Interpersonal Communication

Project Management

Project Planning

Problem-solving

C#

.NET Core 5 & 6

SQL/SSMS/MySQL

JavaScript

React

Material UI

SASS

HTML/CSS

Java/Jakarta EE

TypeScript

Python

Node.js

Version Control/Git/GitHub

EDUCATION

Northern Alberta Institute of Technology, Edmonton — *Digital Media and Information Technology*

2020 - 2023

I led a team of four Software Developers for our Capstone project, finishing the Beta version of a .NET Core educational platform simulating upstream trading within the oil and gas industry. Collaborating with a Business Analyst, we regularly met with the company's chair to align with their vision, meet goals, enhance functionality, and adhere to tight deadlines. We competed against another team of four developers on the same project to deliver the closest version to the client's vision. After presenting our final product to the client, our team was selected for having a more streamlined, user-friendly, functional, and intuitive application. We were then given the opportunity to showcase it to NAIT faculty, alumni, and industry professionals.

Concordia University of Edmonton, Edmonton — Bachelor of Arts in English and Psychology

2016 - 2020

Achieved excellence in collaborative research projects, demonstrating proficiency in conveying data and vital information effectively through written reports and presentations.

PROJECTS

cglinkadesigns.com — React Web Portfolio

I developed a personalized website to showcase my identity, expertise, and coding skills.

Technologies Used: HTML, Custom CSS, JavaScript, React, and EmailJS. The project is responsive across all devices and is deployed and hosted under my own domain using hostinger.com.

IMPACT — Online Learning Curriculum

I led the successful launch of a new curriculum and software developed by Code Ninjas in collaboration with Microsoft MakeCode Arcade. The project started in April 2023 and was completed by the end of May 2023. This involved updating and organizing equipment to ensure a smooth transition for children, designing a training program for instructors to gain hands-on experience, and effectively communicating the changes to parents.

AWARDS

Dean's Honor Roll: 2021/22/23

'Got Yo' Back' award at Code Ninjas for consistently going the extra mile, helping beyond regular duties, maintaining unwavering reliability, and actively participating in various events and volunteer initiatives.

'Black Belt Location 2022' award at Code Ninjas
Windermere for my role in building the dream, providing a black belt experience and being amongst the top 5% in the company.

VOLUNTEER

Autism Edmonton Game Building Workshops - Code Ninjas Windermere

Ninja Arcade for Ukraine Fundraiser - Code Ninjas Windermere

Big Brothers Big Sisters Lego Robotics Workshops - Code Ninjas St. Albert

REFERENCES

Shannon Stevenson | Director of Operations and Owner of Code Ninjas St.

Albert & Windermere **Phone:** (825) 440 5485

Email: shannon.stevenson@codeninjas.com

Annabelle Syms | Director of Customer Service at Code Ninjas

Windermere

Phone: (780) 236 1536

Email: annabelle.syms@gmail.com

Dan Mouris | NAIT Instructor

Email: dmouris@nait.ca